nmat.org.in 2019-01-20

# Privacy Policy

## Overview

We, the Graduate Management Global Connection India Private Ltd., (referred to as “GMGC” or "we" or “us” for the purpose of this agreement) are committed to protecting the privacy of individuals (referred to as " **you** " or " **your** " or “user(s)” who visit the [www.nmat.org.in](http://www.nmat.org.in/) website (the “Website”). When you use our Website, we may collect and store your personal information that is provided by you from time to time. This privacy policy agreement (the “privacy policy”) governs the collection, use and disclosure of personal information collected by GMGC with regard to this Website, the NMAT by GMACTM exam and related products and services available from this Website (“Services”). 

This privacy policy will help you understand the terms and conditions under which information, personal information or sensitive personal data or information (as defined under the Information Technology (Reasonable security practices and procedures and sensitive personal data or information) Rules, 2011 (referred to as “information”) may be provided by you to GMGC, and reasonable measures adopted by us to safeguard such information. You agree that by using our Website you will be bound by this privacy policy and any updates made to this privacy policy. 

By using this Website you expressly agree to the use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with the privacy policy. It is your responsibility to read this privacy policy and check for updates on a regular basis. All updates to this privacy policy will be set out on the Website in a prominent location for your perusal. The changes/updates become effective no sooner than three (3) days after they are set out on the Website. However, changes made for any legal reasons will be effective immediately. In the event you do not agree with the terms and conditions of this privacy policy or any updates/amendments thereto, please send us an email at nmatprivacy@gmac.com stating your disagreement and whether you wish for us to delete the information that has been shared by you with us. You understand that certain testing information, including test scores and records, cannot be altered or deleted. 

## Storage of Information

Any information provided to GMGC or gathered by GMGC pursuant to this privacy policy will be stored by GMGC and its service providers, including as follows: Greenclouds Education Solutions Pvt Ltd located at 6708 DLF City Phase IV, Gurgaon Haryana 122002 India for test registration, customer support, and administration and web site administration; Pearson India Education Services Private Limited located at 301 3rd Floor, JMD Regent Plaza, MG Road, Near Guru Dhronacharya Metro Station, Gurgaon – 122002 India for test registration, administration and scoring; Value First Digital Media Pvt. Ltd., B 13 14, Sector 32 Institutional Area, Delhi, India for sms communications with test takers; and Excelsoft Technologies Private Limited, 1B, Hootagalli Industrial Area, Mysore, India – 570018 for services relating to NMATPrep. Personal information will be transmitted to Pearson VUE located at 5601 Green Valley Drive, Bloomington, Minnesota in the United States for exam administration; and to the Graduate Management Admission Council, located at P.O. Box 2969, Reston, VA 20195 in the United States for administration, business operations, product development, customer support, security, research and marketing purposes. 

If you have questions about this privacy policy, please contact us at: nmatprivacy@gmac.com and phone: 09213027791 or by Postal Mail: Graduate Management Global Connection (India) Private Limited, 405, 4th Floor, Suncity Business Tower, Golf Course Road, Sector 54, Gurgaon 122 002 India. 

## Information Collection

We collect information related to your use of the Website and when you register for the Services. Depending on the product or service you use, we may collect additional information from you including, inter alia, identification or other personal data such as, password, financial information with respect to bank account or credit card or debit card or other payment details. For individuals seeking a disability accommodation for testing, we may request sensitive health information for the purposes of reviewing disability accommodations requests. We may also collect information related to your use of the Website such as IP addresses, user statistics, settings and content submitted by Website visitors. 

For providing the Services, we and our service providers require certain information including personal details, identity proof (such as a photo id), special needs/disability information (if applicable), contact information, communication details, academic and work experience details, graduation details, work experience and market information. You must also consent to and agree to abide by the relevant terms and conditions of the Services that you are purchasing or opting for. 

We collect your photo and identification card information. For test security purposes, GMGC and its service providers may compare photographs provided by individuals that register for the Services with what is collected at the time of testing. GMGC may also use video monitoring at test centers for test security purposes. 

If you consent to participating in a school search service, we will collect certain personal information related to your business school plans and may share your personal information (including your name and email address) and score range with graduate management institutions and strategic partners and they may contact you as part of their marketing outreach. If you consent to participating in surveys and other research, we will use your personal information for survey, product development and other research purposes. Only anonymous, aggregated information is reported in our research reports. 

****Cookies, Pixels, IP Addresses: We use temporary and long term cookies, pixels, web logs, and IP addresses to collect statistical and preference information regarding your interaction with our web sites and track your usage to tailor information and advertising for you to provide a better user experience. 

  * For your information, cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognizes that cookie. Cookies are useful because they allow a website to recognize a user’s device. 
  * We may also use pixels (also known as web beacons or electronic tags) to collect anonymous information about your website usage. A pixel tag is an electronic image, which is ordinarily not visible to users and may be associated with cookies on users’ hard drives. These pixel tags collect anonymous data. These pixels allow third parties to obtain information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, the type of browser used to view the page, and the information in cookies sent by the third party. 
  * Also for your information, an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to a computer by the internet service provider whenever the computer is connected to the internet. Web servers, the computers that deliver web pages, automatically identify a computer by its IP address, and when a page is requested from a website, its servers log the IP address of the computer requesting the page.

You may change your settings, including your marketing preferences, by logging into your account or by contacting Customer Service. 

You can block the use of cookies via your browser, however this may limit your use of our services and products. 

## Information Use 

We use the information we collect from this Website to register you for the Services, provide you the services or products you request, to customize and improve those services and products and the website, for business operations, customer support, marketing purposes and for research and development purposes.

We share your information with our parent company, Graduate Management Admission Council located in the United States, and our service providers who require the information in order to complete their duties. GMGC uses service providers to register you for the Services, administer the Services, provide customer support, collect payment information and for other duties as needed related to the operation and administration of this Website and products and Services. 

For individuals seeking a disability accommodation, your sensitive medical personal information is needed to process and review requests by GMGC and its service providers.

For school search services participants, your contact and background information including your score range will be provided to schools, other institutions and strategic partners that provide graduate management education services or information when you have indicated your interest in receiving such information. 

When you register on the Website and create a profile, we may use your information for research and development purposes in an anonymous, aggregated format. 

We use information collected by cookies and pixels to facilitate your use of the Website, to administer and improve the Website, for marketing and for research and development purposes. 

Targeted Advertising: We (or our advertising service providers) may collect information based on cookies, pixels, web logs and IP addresses concerning Website visitors’ movements on our Website and other Websites and send targeted, interest based advertising based on users’ interests. 

We might use your information to cooperate, as required, with legal proceedings or to prevent or detect fraud or other unlawful activity. 

## Disclosure and Transfer 

When you register for the Services and when you use the Website, you consent to the disclosure of your information to GMGC, its parent Graduate Management Admission Council located in the United States, its service providers, any score recipient you select, and others as necessary to prevent unlawful activity or as required by law.

GMGC may disclose the information related to individuals who create a profile on the Website to its employees, affiliates, and service providers who have a legitimate need to know the information and to fulfill their duties. GMGC also reserves the right to disclose this information under special circumstances, including disclosures required by law, court order or circumstances under which disclosure, in the sole discretion of GMGC, is necessary to protect the legal rights, including the intellectual property rights, of GMGC. 

We and our affiliates may share some or all of your personal information with another business entity should we (or our assets) plan to merge with, or be acquired by that business entity, or re-organization, amalgamation, restructuring of business. Should such a transaction occur, you hereby consent that you have no objection for the transfer of the information provided by you to GMGC, in such manner as may be determined by GMGC with respect to the abovementioned transaction. 

## Retention and Security 

We keep your information only as long as required and then we delete it. We retain your information in order to provide you the following: the services you have requested, meet our governance responsibilities, meet legal requirements and protect against fraud and theft. 

NMAT by GMACTM test scores may be maintained for up to 10 years for the purposes of, including, inter alia, (a) to provide the test takers with access to their NMAT scores, and (b) to protect the integrity of the NMAT test by tracking test taking behavior and analyzing fraudulent activities with respect to the NMAT test. 

To protect the security and integrity of the exam, certain information cannot be altered or destroyed for 10 years, including your test scores and records related to your testing experience. 

GMGC and its service providers have developed security programs that consists of administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to protect your information from unauthorized loss, use, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. This includes the use of encryption such as SSL when transferring your information. 

You may request that we inactivate your account at any time by contacting Customer Service nmatsupport@gmac.com. You should be aware that account deletion requests may limit your ability to use our Services for an extended period of time. As indicated above, information related to your testing, including test scores and records, cannot be altered or destroyed. It may take up to ninety (90) days to fully inactivate or delete your account due to the complexity of the process. You may also change your marketing preferences concerning certain products and services such as school search services by contacting nmatsupport@gmac.com 

## External Links 

The Website contains links to other independently run web sites that are not controlled by GMGC and are not covered by this privacy policy. Our Website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook, LinkedIn, Google+ and Twitter icon and Share button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Website. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it. GMGC is not responsible for the privacy practices, security or content of such web sites. We recommend that you read the privacy policy of any other companies’ or organisations’ website that you link to from our Website. 

## Contact Us 

If you have any questions concerning this Website and privacy policy, please contact us at: nmatsupport@gmac.com or nmatprivacy@gmac.com or call 09213027791. 

## Grievance Officer 

  * **Name:**

Sukant Chakraborty

  *  **Address:**

Graduate Management Global Connection (India) Private Limited, 405, 4th Floor, Suncity Business Tower, Golf Course Road, Sector 54, Gurgaon 122 002 India

  *  **Email:**

nmatprivacy@gmac.com

  *  **Phone:**

09213027791

  *  **Time:**

Mon to Fri (9:00 to 18:00) IST

##  Governing Law 

This privacy policy shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of India, without effect to any principles of conflicts of law. 

##  Dispute Resolution 

All disputes and claims between you and GMGC related to this privacy policy shall be exclusively submitted to arbitration under the Arbitration and Conciliation Act, 1996, as amended, by a sole arbitrator appointed by GMGC. Arbitrator’s decisions shall be final and binding on the parties. The seat of arbitration shall be Gurgaon. You must submit any legal notices to the attention of the General Counsel, Graduate Management Global Connection (India) Pvt. Ltd., 405, 4th Floor, Suncity Business Tower, Sector 54, DLF Golf Course Road, Gurgaon – 122 002, India.
